Jacob Seidenberg Additional records 5229
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jacob Seidenberg Additional records
1964-1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Seidenberg, Jacob
5229
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Jacob Seidenberg's arbitration files.
5556972
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 26, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Jacob Seidenberg (1914-1996) was a government official who specialized in labor arbitration and non-discrimination contracts, and wrote extensively on labor law and negotiations. He graduated from Temple University in 1937 and received a law degree from the University of Pennsylvania Law School in 1941. During the 1940s he was an attorney with the U.S. War Department, the National War Labor Board and the National Wage Stabilization Board. In 1948 he went to graduate school at Cornell University, from which he earned his Ph.D. in industrial and labor relations in 1951. In 1951 he joined the staff of the President's Committee on Government Contract Compliance. The Committee was abolished by President Dwight D. Eisenhower in August 1953 by Executive Order 10479 and was succeeded by the President's Committee on Government Contracts. Seidenberg was appointed Executive Director of the new committee and served until January 1960 when he resigned to become a full-time labor arbitrator. The Committee was responsible for enforcing non-discrimination clauses in government contracts, worked with private businesses to help them overcome job discrimination, and developed educational programs against ethnic and racial discrimination. The chairman was Vice President Richard Nixon, and the vice chairman was Secretary of Labor James P. Mitchell. In later years Seidenberg served on a number of boards of inquiry involving labor disputes. From 1970 to 1975 he was chairman of the Federal Services Impasses Panel which settled deadlocks in federal labor negotiations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5007: U.S. Emergency Board No. 175 Transcripts and Exhibits 5027: U.S. Emergency Board No. 178 Transcripts 5031 A&B: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5032: Jacob Seidenberg Injunction Study 5175: Jacob Seidenberg Taft-Hartley Maritime Dispute Records 5194: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Files 5217: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Case Files 5468: Jacob Seidenberg Arbitration files 5519: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5571: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5605: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5635: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5666: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5706: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5756: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5773: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5808: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5900: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5935: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5953: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5988: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Sources; Seidenberg, Jacob
5556972
- Ellicott Machinery - Dist. 50 - Allied and Technical Workers - FMCS 71A/5011, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- P.L. Board No. 613 UTU - Niagara Junction RR, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Mueller Co - 1AM FMCS 71A/3366, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- P.L. Board No. 726 P+LE- BLE, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Abex Corp. - American Brakeblok Div. UAW - Reg. 8 - Local Union #149, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- EAL - Mechanical Dept. System Bdg. Adjustment #6-65, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- SBA #683 BLE + A.ToSF(Western Lines), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- United Steel Workers - Local 5075 and New Jersey Zinc Co. - Austinville, VA FMCS 67A/2173, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 1AM Lodge# 2124 Fairchild - Heller Aircraft Services Div. FMCS 67A/2970, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Brewery Workers Local 10 and Carling, National F&M Schaefer Brewing Company, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Special Board of Adjustment #752 - REA - BPAC, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Amalgamated Meat Cutters - Local 272 - Gen. H. Meyer + Son - FMCS 71A/6220, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Willingboro Board of Education, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- P.L. #468 PC(New Haven) BLE, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- C+O - B+O - UTU (T) P.L. Board No. 509, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Frederick County Bd of Education - Frederick County Truckers Assoc., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- AirLine Dispatcher Association and Eastern air Lines Inc. Cases nos: 3-66: 4-66-5-66, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- USWA - Local 2556 Lynching Founding Company, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- FMCS Arbitration File No: 66A/3480 P. Haburgh Plate Glass Co. + (Local #1 AC+AW), 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Glamorgan Pipe + Foundry and USWA - Local 1264, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- ALPA - EAL - 34-66 (Bard Grievance), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- VOA and Natl. F Edington Lodge 1476 - USIA (153-USIA-1), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- FMCS 67A/3599 IBT Local 515D Philip Van Hensen, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Washington Beef Co. Amalgamated Meat Cutters, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- P.L. Board No. 207 - Milwaukee B.R.T., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- FMCS 30A/3999 Carbordum Company - OCAWIU Local 3-816, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- EAL + IAM, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- SBA #695 R.F.P + ORCB, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- T-H Proceeding + Hearing General Electric + et. Al., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Washington (D.C.) Newspaper Publishers Assoc. and Columbia Typographical Union - FMCS 67A/612, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- P.L. Board no. 3 Western Maryland vs. BRC, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Assoc. of Scientists + Prof. Engineering Pers. Vs. RCA L-44696-PHI-L-691-64, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- SBA #679 Norfolk Southern v. BRT, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- I.A.M. District Lodge 100 v. EAL Case no: 16465 165-66, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- EAL vs. ALPA #59-66, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- FMC Corp. - Ordinance Div. and UAW-AFL-CIO Local 348 (FMCS), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- SBA #654 EJE v. BLF+E, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- CWA - District #2 and General Telephone of Southeast/ FMCS 66A/5414, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- USW #Local 2556 and Lynchburg Foundry Co - Lynchburg, Va., 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- SBA #667 Lmg. Island RR v. BLE, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- SBA #660 RG+P and BLE, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- FMCS -66A/2265 American Lara Corp and AIW- Local 222, AFL-CIO, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- SBA no. 643 Central Vermont Railway Co. BRT +, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- ALPA vs. Eastern Airlines (Hamlin Grievance), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Yale Lock + Hardwean Div. of Yale+Towne vs. United Steel Workers - Local 4505 FMCS 66A/570, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- "282 Special Board of Adjust." RF+PRR Co. and BRT, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- SBA #604 Bangor and Aroostook RR Co. vs. BRT, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Public Law Board No. 361 - Akron + Barkerton Belt RR - UTU (T), 1971 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- P.L. Board No. 516 Chicago + Northwestern - BRS, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Penn Central - Railroad Yardmasters of America -, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- RCA - AFTE - Local 241 AAA 1430 0807-69M, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- P.L. #206 - Penn Central and BLFE, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- P.L. Board No. 378 Penn Central - BLE, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- 286-Navships - 37/ Office of Supervisors, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- P.L. Board No. 474 Award No. 14, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- FMCS 70A/3499 Newport News shipbuilding - Peninsula Shipbuilding Assoc., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Awards - P.L. Board No. #223 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Public Law Board No. 223 - Penn Central (Southern Region) BRT, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Naval Supply Center -IAM Lodge 97, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Jos. Schlitz Brewing Co. IBT - Local no. 391, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Sperry Rand (Electro Components) -IAM - Lodge 721 FMCS 70A/7805, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- P.L. Board No. 459 - B+O and BLE, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- P.L. Board No. 217 Southern Railway/ System (Cultural of Iso) and SUNA, 1966-1970 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- WareHouse, Retail + Mart Ander Employees - Local 590 - Luby AAA- 1430 1014- 69k Chevrolet Co., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- P.L. Board No. A24 Montour Railroad Company, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Greenbelt Consumer Service - Local 400 Retail Clerk Int. Assoc., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Brewery Workers Local Union 10 - F+M Schaeffer Brewing Co. AAA 143000945-69, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Atcheson, Topeka + Sante Fe - BLS P.L. Board No. 86, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- P.L. Board no. 184 BLF+E and A+WP - W of A, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Bureau of Customs -, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Hail + Restaurant Workers - Natural Lawyers Club, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Amalgamated Meat Cutters (Local 272) - Geo H Meyers Sons FMCS 69A/4542, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- South Buffalo Railway Company - BRT P.L. Board no. 239, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Teamsters Local No. 7640 Penna State University (AAA) 14-30-0726-68, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Assoc. of Scientists + Prof. Eng. Personnel and RCA - AAA - Case No. 14-30-0739-66, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- International Pager Co. and United Papermakers and Paperworkers Local 265-A, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- P.L. Board no. 190 BLF+E and Sante Fe (Coast Lines), 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- P.L. Board no. 199 Florida East Coast - BRT, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Harbison Walker Refractories Company and Local 14601 UMVA, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Local #1 Cement. Lime + Gypsum Workers Int. Union - General Portland Grant Co. 68A/7204, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Allied Aviation Fuelings Co. - IAM - District 141 FMCS 68A/6887, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- AAA-L-48837-PHI-L-735-65 United Steel Workers-Local 5861 and National Wine Products Corp., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- IAM + Mueller Company FMCS 68A/4878, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Nashville Bridge Company - Ironworkers Union - Local #733 - FMCS 68A/6552, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Tennessee Forging Steel Co. -USA FMCS 69A/212, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Tennessee Products+Chemical Corp. - U.S.W.A. FMCS 69A/852, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- P.L. Board no. 205 chicago, milwaukee BRT, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Butler MF Co./ FMCS District 50 -UM, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- SBA #570 RED - Nat'l. Railway LHR Conf., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- SBA #740, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- BLF+E- P.L. #183, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- A+P Company IBT - Local Unions No. 322 FMCS 68A/4824, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Public Law Board No. 294 - EJE - BRT, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- GEM Stores, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- P.L. Board No. 117 BRT - Atlanta Joint Terminal, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Stauffer Chemical company - Int. Union of Operating Engineers - FMCS 69A/4441, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- ALPA #1, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- EAL v. ALPA - ALPA - 7690 EAL -68-2, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Ari Lift. ALPA - TWA, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Mr. J. Seedenberg Pl Bd. 254, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Public Board No. 254 - Long Island Railroad - BLFE, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Ozite Corporation - URW FMCS 69A/3757, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- AFTE v. RCA 14-30-0408-68 (AA), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Glidden - Dunkee Division - UMWA FMCS 69A/5920, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Walker Mfg. Co. -UAW- FMCS 69A/3891, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- AJT-AWPRR - BERT-BLE-BLFE -SBA #746, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Atlantic Steel Co. and United Steel Workers of America FMCS 69A/391, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Emergency Board No. 175, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Mead Packaging - Atlanta Printing Specialties Union 69A/3181, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- General Portland Cement Company vs. Local No. 130, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- P.L. Brand No. 64 Savannah + Atlanta RR. + BLF+E, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- SBA #625 Indiana Harbor Bill RR Co. vs BLF+E, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Navajo Freight Lines -IBT FMCS 71A/4145, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- District 50 Olin Chemical - Saltville, Virginia, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- P.L. Board No. 472 - Lehigh Valley - BLE, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- P.L. Board No. 52 - River Terminal RR Co. - UTU, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Olin Corporation - Int. Union District 50 (Local 12138) FMCS 71A/3559, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Arbitration Board - DC - BRAC (Rotella Case), 1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Special Board No. 743 Chciago. Burlington + Quincy RR + BRAC, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- P.L. Board No. 543 - Sante Fe - BLE, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Competition District Council Equitable Construction Company FMCS 70/10007, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- P.L. Board No. 474 - Southern RR System - BLE, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- District 50 - Alllied + Technical Workers (Meed Corp - Woodward Iron Dov. FMCS 70A/9016, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Rubatex Corp- URW FMCS 71A/630, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- NII Laboratory Furniture Int. Woodworkers of America FMCS 70A/10045, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- AAA-14 30 0563 70K R+F Transportation co. - Truck Drivers-Helpers Local 355, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- P.L. Board No. 385 UTU, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Allied Chemical - District 50- UMWA FMCS 70A/7385, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- P.L. Board No. 453 - Western Maryland - BRAC - TU - Division, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Lockheed - Georgia Company and IAM - Lodge #709 + FMCS 70A/6992, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Public Law Board No. 440 - UTU - Union Pacific RR, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- P.L. Board No. 542 UTU(T) Pittsburgh Chartiers + Legge, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Seaboard World Airline - ALPA System Board of Adjustment, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 27)